<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/stylesheets/rss.css" type="text/css"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Alice, Bob, and Mallory: Simple security tokens needed</title>
    <link>http://alicebobandmallory.com/articles/2007/03/27/secure-and-simple-security-tokens-needed</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>metasyntactics</description>
    <item>
      <title>Simple security tokens needed</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an earlier &lt;a href="/articles/2007/02/05/trojans-and-one-time-passwords"&gt;post &lt;/a&gt; I mentioned that a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_token#Digital_signatures"&gt;security token&lt;/a&gt; that lets you sign your transactions is one way to go to get more secure Internet banking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now &lt;a href="http://www.bth.se/tek/aps/mbo.nsf/pages/1df251df5df1b090c12572a6002389b1!OpenDocument"&gt;a couple of swedish students&lt;/a&gt; have shown (by also using the problem I mentioned in this &lt;a href="/articles/2007/02/26/change-your-default-passwords"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;) that a security token both needs to be used in a secure manner and that it also needs to be simple for the user to know what he is actually signing. According to the &lt;a href="http://computersweden.idg.se/2.2683/1.100636"&gt;press&lt;/a&gt; it seems that they did this as a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man_in_the_middle_attack"&gt;man-in-the-middle attack&lt;/a&gt;. This is just speculations but it seems the reason that this were possible were that the user did not have a clear view of what he was signing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It &lt;a href="http://sakerhet.idg.se/2.1070/1.100636?articleRenderMode=listpostings#"
&gt;could&lt;/a&gt; have been done something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redirect the user to a fake site (and hope that he does not 
investigate the certificate).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask for username and challenge the user with the verification code and then login to the bank in the background.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to add a new account for transfers and then tell the user he mistyped and has to login again while challenging him to verify the new account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transfer money the same way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bank has &lt;a href="http://www.swedbank.se/sst/inf/out/infOutWww1/0,,1842_m109_m44_398348,00.html"&gt;&lt;i&gt;solved&lt;/i&gt; the problem&lt;/a&gt; by adding a 9 before all login codes. I'm not convinced this is simple and obvious enough for the users. One way to make it simple could be a security device with buttons labeled "login", "sign account" and "sign amount" or such.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT: Now it has started to arrive phishing mails that asks the customers of Swedbank to install ssl3.exe... &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2007 22:46:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:2cf7d0be-08f1-4941-848d-cf3fbd5378e2</guid>
      <author>Jonas Elfström</author>
      <link>http://alicebobandmallory.com/articles/2007/03/27/secure-and-simple-security-tokens-needed</link>
      <category>Security</category>
      <trackback:ping>http://alicebobandmallory.com/articles/trackback/20</trackback:ping>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Simple security tokens needed" by Jonas Elfström</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will check out WiKID as soon as possible. &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/"&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;  removed a couple of underscores from the URL you supplied. I might have to disable Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 08:41:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:8e19ea7f-2dd7-4070-84cc-c33430cab0c7</guid>
      <link>http://alicebobandmallory.com/articles/2007/03/27/secure-and-simple-security-tokens-needed#comment-24</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Simple security tokens needed" by Nick Owen</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jonas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glad to have found your blog.  Be glad that banks in your country are putting forth such a strong effort. (Although I was not able to read the articles in Swedish. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would be interested in your thoughts on our two-factor solution as it applies to online banking.  It is interesting in that because we use public key cryptography, we can have cryptographically distinct OTP mechanisms within a single client (or across multiple clients of course).  We also can perform host authentication for SSL websites, preventing MITM attacks - and we launch the default browser to the correct website, making it easier for the user, which I agree is paramount. You can find more info here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wikid.com/two-factor-authentication/industry/anti_phishing_2_factor/"&gt;http://www.wikid.com/two-factor-authentication/industry/anti&lt;em&gt;phishing&lt;/em&gt;2_factor/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m of the opinion that banks will have to do session, host/mutual, &amp;amp; transaction authentication before long.  Seems like it will occur last in the US.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2007 16:11:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:e6bd7f3a-8fe3-4a33-b82b-24d6d075314f</guid>
      <link>http://alicebobandmallory.com/articles/2007/03/27/secure-and-simple-security-tokens-needed#comment-23</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
